有多少？
How little?
(普罗维登斯 罗得岛)
像你画的"一点"眼影那么少
Why don't you put on a little eye shadow?
而且你知道 这些东西也太不专业了
And, you know, all this stuff is just like-It's just very unprofessional.
别碰鱼饵
Don't touch the troll.
你约会的时候你妈妈常这么说话？
Is that what your mom used to say to your dates?
把鱼饵放下 否则我就在你两眼之间钉个钉子
Put the trolls down or I'll put a staple right between your.
我知道这很困难
Now, I know it's hard.
在你低落的时候很难抬头看
It's hard to look up when you're down.
很难向上看到光明
It's hard to look up and see the light.
但我要告诉你…
But I'm here to tell you, folks...
上帝与你同在
the Lord is with you.
你不会痛苦
You don't have to suffer.
也不会迷惑
You don't have to be lost.
上帝正在对你说话
The Lord is talking to you right now.
他在说"你是我的子民 你有你的使命"
He's saying, "You are my child and you have a purpose."
你觉得上帝抛弃了你？让我告诉你吧 不
You think God forgot about you? I tell you, no.
你们只需侧耳倾听
All you gotta do is listen.
难道你们听不到天使的歌唱？
Can't you just hear those angels singing?
是不是很动听啊？
Isn't it beautiful?
是时候了
It's time.
是时候接受他传达的信息了
It's time to receive the message he's sending.
是时候倾听上帝的声音了
It's time to listen to the word of God.
你听到天堂之声了吗？你说你没有听到吗？
Can you hear the glory? I said, can't you just hear it?
你没听到上帝的声音吗？
I say, can't you just hear the glory?
哦 上帝啊
My God.
[邪恶力量 第2季第13集]
早上好 你不是常来的那个人
Good morning. You're not the usual guy.
不是 呃… 我是替班的
No, uh, just filling in.
今天你感觉如何 格洛里亚？
So how you feeling today, Gloria?
从没感觉这么好过
I've never felt better.
最近没有感觉不安？
So no disturbances lately?
你是问我有没有精神错乱？
You mean, am I stark raving cuckoo for Cocoa Puffs?
我没那么说 没关系
- I didn't say that. - It's all right.
我知道大家怎么想的
I know what people must think.
你怎么想？我想我看到的是真的
- What do you think? - I think what I saw was real.
我想知道你看到了什么
I'd like to know what you saw.
和新闻上说的一样
It was all over the news.
我刺穿了一个人的心脏
I stabbed a man in the heart.
为什么这么做？
Why would you do that?
因为那是上帝的意志
Because it was God's will.
上帝和你说话了？
Did God talk to you?
我觉得上帝太忙了 不会有时间"家访"
I get the sense God's a little busy for house calls.
不 他… 他派了别人来
No, he... He sent someone.
别人？
Someone?
一位天使
An angel.
伴随着那种美丽的白光出现在我面前
It came to me in this beautiful white light.
我的心中充满了那种…
And it filled me with this...
感觉
feeling.
那… 那很难描述
It's hard to describe.
然后天使…
And this angel...
传达了上帝的旨意
Spoke God's word.
那旨意是… 让你去杀人？
And the word was to kill someone?
我知道这听起来很怪
I know it sounds strange.
但我所作的事情非常重要
But what I did was very important.
我帮助他惩罚了一个罪人
I helped him smite an evil man.
我是被选中…
I was chosen...
去救赎的
for redemption.
那个被你杀的男人… 是天使给的名字吗？
This man you stabbed, did the angel give you his name?
没有 他只告诉我等待"信号"
No. He just told me to wait for the sign.
就在第二天 我在那人的门口旁看到了"信号"
And the very next day I saw it, right beside the man's doorway.
我就明白了 为什么杀他？
- And I knew. - Why him?
我只知道那个天使告诉我
I just know what the angel told me.
那个男人已经罪恶到骨子里了
That this man was guilty to his deepest foundations.
这对我来说就足够了
And that was good enough for me.
嘿
Hey.
嗨 老弟 你真该试试
Hey. Man, you gotta try this.
"魔法手指"里真的有魔法
There really is magic in the magic fingers.
迪恩 你怎么这么喜欢这个 我都有点不自在了
Dean, you're enjoying that way too much. It's kind of making me uncomfortable.
那你让我干嘛？
What am I supposed to do?
是你把我关在这儿的 都快无聊死了
You got me on lockdown. I'm bored out of my skull.
嘿 上了11点新闻的银行劫犯是你 又不是我
Hey, you were the bank robber on the 11:00 news, not me.
让你走进一个政府机构太冒险了
We can't risk you just walking into a government facility.
哦 见鬼
Aw, damn it.
那可是我最后一个硬币了
That was my last quarter.
嘿
Hey.
你有硬币么？
You got any quarters?
没有
No.
- 那么 你混进去找到了那个疯子妓女？- 对
- So did you get in to see that crazy hooker? - Yeah.
格洛里亚·瑟特尼克 我说不好她是不是真的疯了
Gloria Sytnik. And I'm not so sure she's crazy.
但她真的相信… 她和天使有约？"Touched by an Angel" CBS电视剧《天使有约》
But she seriously believes that she was touched by an angel?
对 炫目的白光 内心的狂喜 还有使命
Yeah. Blinding light, feelings of spiritual ecstasy, the works.
我是说 她被关在与世隔绝的病房里 心灵却非常平静
I mean, she's living in a locked ward and she's totally at peace.
哦 是啊 你说得没错听起来完全正常
Oh, yeah, you're right. Sounds completely sane.
她捅死的那家伙呢？呃 卡尔·格利
- What about the dude she stabbed? - Uh, Carl Gulley.
她说她杀了他是因为他是恶魔 - 是吗？
- Said she killed him because he was evil. - Was he?
- 不知道 我没发现他有什么污点
I don't know. I couldn't find any dirt on him.
没有犯罪记录 在大学图书馆工作 朋友众多
He didn't have a criminal record, he worked at the campus library, had lots of friends.
还是个虔诚的信徒
- He was a churchgoer. - Hmm.
那么格洛里亚就是那种标准的疯子？
So then Gloria's just your standard-issue wacko.
我是说 她又不是第一个这种
I mean, she wouldn't be the first nut job in history...
借信仰之名杀人的神经病 明白我的意思吗？
to kill in the name of religion, know what I mean?
的确不是 但她是镇上第二个 听从天使的指示杀人的
No, but she's the second in town to murder because an angel told them to.
有点怪 你不觉得么？是怪 也许是超自然现象
- A little bit odd, don't you think? - Odd, yes. Supernatural, maybe.
但是说到天使 那不可能
But angels? I don't think so.
为什么？因为那种东西根本不存在 萨姆
- Why not? - Because there's no such thing, Sam.
迪恩 关于天使的传说
Dean, there's 10 times as much lore about angels...
是我们猎杀的那些东西的10倍多啊
as there is about anything we've hunted.
独角兽的传说也有好多呢
Hey, there's a ton of lore on unicorns too.
据说他们在银色月光上奔跑 从屁股里往外喷彩虹
I hear that they ride on silver moonbeams and they shoot rainbows out of their ass.
等等 独角兽不存在吗？
Wait, there's no such thing as unicorns?
你可真可爱 我只是说 老弟
That's cute. I'm just saying, man, there's some legends you just-
有些传说你得归到"狗屁"那类里去
You file under bull crap.
天使就在你的"狗屁"传说名单上？- 没错
- And you got angels on the bull-crap list. - Yup.
- 为什么？
Why?
- 因为我从没看见过 - 那又怎么样？
- Because I've never seen one. - So what?
就是说我只相信我看到的东西
So I believe in what I can see.
迪恩 咱们俩见过的那些东西 大部分人连做梦都没见过
Dean, you and I have seen things most people couldn't even dream about.
说的对 是我们亲眼所见的 那就是确凿的证据
Exactly. With our own eyes. That's hard proof.
好吗？但我从没见过任何类似天使的东西
Okay? But in all this time, I have never seen anything that looks like an angel.
要是有 你不觉得我们早该碰到了
If they existed, we would've crossed paths with them...
或者至少听说有人碰见过
or know someone that crossed paths with them.
不 这肯定是魔鬼或恶灵干的
No. This is a demon or a spirit.
找了几个又疯又傻的家伙
They find people a few fries short of a Happy Meal...
骗他们随便找个人杀了
and they trick them into killing these randoms.
也许
Maybe.
咱们能不能… 我快闲得发疯了 去格洛里亚的公寓看看 行不？
Can we just? I'm going stir-crazy. Hey, let's go by Gloria's apartment, huh?
我刚从那儿回来 什么也没有
I was just there. Nothing.
没有硫磺 EMF也没有反应
No sulfur, no EMF.
没看见毛茸茸的白羽毛？
You didn't see any fluffy, white wing feathers?
可是格洛里亚说过天使在卡尔·格利的
But Gloria did say the angel gave her a sign.
门口留下某种"信号"
Right beside Carl Gulley's doorway.
也许他家里有什么东西 值得去看看
Could be something at his house. It's worth checking out.
嘿 萨姆
Oh, hey, Sam.
我想我找到了
Think I found it.
上天的信号
It's a sign from up above.
我觉得我学到了宝贵的一课
Well, I think I learned a valuable lesson.
新年过后得记着把圣诞装饰都摘下来
Take down your Christmas decorations after New Year's...
不然就会被上帝派来的妓女切成碎片
or you might get filleted by a hooker from God. Ha.
我心里暗笑呢
I'm laughing on the inside.
格洛里亚说那个男人已经罪恶到骨子里了
You know, Gloria said the guy was "guilty to his deepest foundations."
你觉得她是指字面意义上的"地下室"？
You think she literally meant the foundation?
找到什么了？
Hey.You got something?
这是什么？
What is it?
指甲
It's a fingernail.
真是个虔诚善良的图书馆员啊
So much for the innocent, churchgoing librarian.
不管告诉格洛里亚的是什么东西
Well, whatever spoke to Gloria about this...
它都说中了 这个我敢保证
knew what it was talking about, I'll give you that.
什么事？
Yes?
嗨 我叫扎克
Hi, my name is Zach.
有什么事吗？
Can I help you?
我们有一个助教的摩托车和面包车
We got a minor T.A. involving a, uh, motorcycle and a van.
在第二十八棵松树的角落里
This is at the corner of, uh, 28th and Pine.
第二十八颗
28th and Pine.
你换硬币了吗？
Did you bring quarters?
老兄 我可不会助长你这种病态的爱好
Dude, I'm not enabling your sick habit.
你就跟实验室的小白鼠一样 把食物忘到一边
You're one of those lab rats that pushes the pleasure button...
只知道不停的享乐直到饿死
instead of the food button until it dies.
你说什么呢？我吃饭的 还找到了新消息
What are you talking about? I eat. And I got news.
- 我也是 - 好吧 你先说
- Me too. - All right. You go first.
今年大学里一共有三个学生失踪 所有人最后出现的地点都是图书馆
Three students disappeared off the campus this year. All were last seen at the library.
- 卡尔·格利工作的那个图书馆 - 对
- Where Carl Gulley worked. - Yup.
- 变态的混蛋 - 那么格洛里亚说的那个天使
- Sick bastard. - So Gloria's angel
- 天使？- 好吧 不管是什么
- Angel? - Okay, whatever this thing is.
- 不管是什么它又动手了 - 什么？
- Whatever it is, it struck again. - What?
我偷听了警察的无线电 发现了这个家伙 扎克·施密特
I was listening to the police radio. There was this guy, uh, Zach Smitt.
他喝醉了 昨晚走到一个陌生人家门口
Some local drunk. He went up to a stranger's front door last night...
一刀刺透他的心脏 - 他后来去警察局自首了？
- ...stabbed him in the heart. - He went to the police and confessed?
没错 罗玛·唐尼让他做的
Yup. Roma Downey made him do it.
现在 我 嗯…
Now, I, uh...
有受害者的住址
got the victim's address.
找到什么了？
Find anything?
弗兰克喜欢收藏购物目录 我只找到这些 你呢？
Well, Frank liked his catalog-shopping. That's about all I got. You?
没有什么
Not much here.
除了他计算机有个加密的档案 等会儿
Except he's got this one locked file on his computer that... Hold on.
现在没了
Not anymore.
老天啊
God.
- 怎么？- 他发了好多邮件
- What? - Uh, he has all these e-mails. Dozens.
给一个叫詹尼弗的女士
To this lady named Jennifer.
这位女士才13岁
This lady who's 13 years old.
哦 我不想听下去了
Aw, I don't wanna hear this.
看起来他们是在聊天室认识的
Looks like they met in a chat room.
这些邮件都涉及到私事 迪恩
These e-mails are pretty personal, Dean.
瞧这个
Look at that.
- 他们订了见面的时间和地点 - 太棒了
- Setting up a time and place to meet. - Great.
他们本该今天见面
They were supposed to meet today.
我猜要是捅人 这个时间挑的不错
I guess if you're gonna stab someone, good timing.
我不知道 这太奇怪了
I don't know, man, this is weird, you know.
我是说 当然有些鬼魂是为了报仇杀人
Sure, some spirits are out for vengeance.
但这一个简直是在做好事 就像…
But this one's almost like a do-gooder. Like a
复仇天使？
Avenging angel?
还有别的解释吗 迪恩？
How else do you explain it, Dean?
三个受害者之间没有任何关联 心脏都被捅了一刀
Three guys, not connected to each other, all stabbed through the heart?
其中至少两个都是罪该万死
At least two were world-class pervs.
- 而且我敢说 如果你深入调查剩下的那个 - 嘿
- I bet if you dug deep on the other guy. - Hey.
- 什么？- 你说过卡尔·格利是个信徒 对不对？
- What? - Carl Gulley was a churchgoer, right?
- 是啊 - 他去的哪个教堂？
- Yeah. - What was the name of his church?
"天使之后"？
Our Lady of the Angels?
果然是这个名字 看起来弗兰克也去同一个教堂
Of course that'd be the name. Looks like Frank went to the same church.
那么 你们愿意加入这个教区？
You're interested in joining the parish?
我们俩每周日不去教堂就浑身难受
We just don't feel right unless we hit church every Sunday.
你们以前住在哪儿？
Where'd you say you lived? Uh-
得克萨斯的普雷蒙
Premont, Texas. Yup.
真的？那可是个不错的小镇
Really? That's a nice town.
在圣特里沙教区 你们肯定认识那里的神父了
St. Theresa's Parish. You must know the priest there.
当然了 是奥马利神父
Sure, yeah. No, it's, uh, Father O'Malley.
我认识的是一位肖尼西神父
Hmm, I know a Father Shaughnessy.
肖尼西神父 没错 我刚才说的是什么？
Shaughnessy. Exactly. What did I say?
我们很高兴能加入 神父
We're just happy to be here now, Father.
我们也很希望你们加入 我们需要一些年轻人
And we're happy to have you. We could use some young blood around here.
我想问一下 无意冒犯 但这周围的环境…
Hmm. Listen, I gotta ask, and no offense, but the neighborhood-?
这里的治安有些不好 我不否认
It's gone to seed a little, there's no denying.
但这才是教堂的重要意义所在
That's why what the church does here is important.
就像我常说的 你可以期待奇迹 但同时也要努力工作
You can expect a miracle, but in the meantime, you work your butt off.
对 我们听说了那些谋杀
We heard about the murders.
是的 受害者都是我的教民 我和他们认识很久了
Yes. The victims were parishioners of mine. I'd known them for years.
那些犯人都说是天使让他们做的？
And the killers said that an angel made them do that?
是的 都是些被误导的灵魂
Yes. Misguided souls.
居然认为上帝的信使会煽动他们杀人
To think that God's messenger would appear and incite people to murder.
- 真是悲惨 - 这么说 你不相信天使？
- It's tragic. - So you don't believe in those angel yarns?
哦 不是的 我当然相信 这是我工作的一部分
Oh, no, I absolutely believe. Kind of goes with the job description.
神父 那是米迦勒 对吗？
Father, that's Michael, right?
是的 天使长米迦勒 手持火焰之剑
That's right, the Archangel Michael with the flaming sword.
他是对抗魔鬼的战士
A fighter of demons.
是击败邪恶的光明力量
And a holy force against evil.
看来不是印在明信片上的 那种大家心目中的天使形象
So they're not really the Hallmark-card version that everybody thinks?
他们很勇猛 对不对？高度警惕的
They're fierce, right? Vigilant.
我比较喜欢他们可爱的形象 而不是这么愤怒
I like to think of them as more loving than wrathful.
但… 的确 很多关于圣经的画像 都把天使表现为神的战士
But, yes, a lot of Scripture paints angels as God's warriors.
"有主的使者站在他们旁边" "主的荣光四面照着他们
An angel of the Lord appeared to them, glory of the Lord shone down upon them...
牧羊人甚为恐慌"
and they were terrified.
路加福音 第二章 第九节
Luke 2:9.
- 谢谢和你的谈话 神父 - 我很荣幸
Thank you for speaking with us. It's my pleasure.
- 希望能再见到你们 - 神父 这是什么？
- Hope to see you again. - Hey, Father. What's all that for?
哦 那是给格雷戈瑞神父的 他曾经是这里的神父
Oh, that's for Father Gregory. He was a priest here.
曾经？
Was?
他就是在这台阶上去世的
Passed away right on these steps.
- 被葬在教堂的地墓 - 这是什么时候发生的？
- He's interred in the church crypt. - When did this happen?
两个月前 有人为了抢车钥匙枪杀了他
Two months ago. He was shot for his car keys.
- 很抱歉 - 我也是
- I'm sorry. - Yeah, me too.
他是个好朋友
He was a good friend.
我连为他做临终圣礼的时间都没有
I didn't even have time to administer his last rites.
但就像我说的 这里的环境不太好
But like I said, it's a tough neighborhood.
自从他死后 我就全心全意地祈祷
Ever since he died, I've been praying my heart out.
- 祈祷什么？- 解脱…
- For what? - For deliverance.
从那些暴力和血腥里解脱
From the violence and the bloodshed around here.
我们真的需要一点神的干预了
We could use a little divine intervention, I suppose.
好 神父 谢谢你 我们会再来的
Padre, thanks. We'll see you again.
好了 这下就说得通了
It's all starting to make sense.
虔诚的教士死于暴力
Devoted priest dies a violent death.
这可是变成恶灵复仇的上好材料
That's vengeful-spirit material right there.
他知道那些人的罪 因为他们都在这个教堂忏悔
He knew the other stiffs, they went to church here.
我敢打赌 因为是他们的神父
I'm willing to bet, because he was their priest...
他知道他们隐藏的秘密
he knew things about them nobody else knew.
还有
Then again...
两个月前雷诺神父 开始祈求上帝的帮助 对吧？
Father Reynolds started praying for God's help two months ago, right?
- 也正好是那些凶杀开始的时间 - 哦 好了 你怎么回事？
- About the time all this started happening. - Come on. What's your deal?
- 你什么意思？- 我承认我是有点无神论
- What do you mean? - I'll admit, I'm a bit of a skeptic...
但你什么时候变成700俱乐部的信徒了？
but since when are you all Mr. 700 Club?
说真的 从一开始 你就想相信那些天使的胡话
Seriously, from the get-go, you've been willing to buy this angel crap.
然后呢？难道你要开始每天祈祷？
I mean, what's next, you gonna start praying every day?
没错
I do.
- 什么？- 我每天都祈祷
- What? - I do pray every day.
已经很长时间了
I have for a long time.
又了解你一点了
The things you learn about a guy...
好了 我们去看看格雷戈瑞神父的墓
Come on, let's check out Father Gregory's grave.
萨姆 快点 别磨蹭了
Sam, come on. Get the lead out.
萨姆？
Sammy.
萨姆 嘿
Sam. Hey.
- 没事吧？- 没事
You okay? - Yeah.
是的
Yeah.
我没事
I'm okay.
来
Come on.
- 你看到它了 对吧？是不是？- 对
- You saw it, didn't you? Didn't you? - Yeah.
对 迪恩 我看到了天使
Yeah, Dean, I saw an angel.
好吧 来
All right.
我不想喝酒
I don't want a drink.
你为什么觉得看到了… 呃… 天使？
So, what makes you think you saw a, uh, angel?
因为…
It just...
它出现在我面前 我…
It appeared before me and just...
我全身都充满了一种感觉 你知道 就像…
This feeling washed over me, you know, like peace.
像那种平静 感恩
Like grace.
好了 幸福男孩
Okay, ecstasy boy.
也许该给你找根 亮晶晶的手杖和休斯博士的漂亮帽子
Maybe we'll get you some glow sticks and a nice Dr. Seuss hat?
迪恩 我没开玩笑
Dean, I'm serious.
它和我说话 知道我是谁
It spoke to me. It knew who I was.
那只是个鬼魂 萨姆
It's just a spirit, Sam.
又不是第一个能读心的鬼魂了
Okay? And it's not the first one to be able to read people's minds.
好了 让我猜猜
Okay, let me guess...
你被选中去惩罚某个罪人？
you were personally chosen to smite some sinner.
只需等着神圣的小蝙蝠给你个信号 是吗？
You just gotta wait for some divine Bat Signal, is that it?
对 没错
Yeah, actually.
太好了
Great.
我猜你没问那个坏家伙 到底犯了什么坏事吧？
I don't suppose you asked what this bad guy did?
实际上我问了 迪恩
Actually, I did, Dean.
天使也告诉我了
And the angel told me.
他现在
He hasn't done anything...
还没做什么
yet.
但他会的
But he will.
哦 这简直 我可不信
Oh, this is-I don't believe this.
迪恩 天使从来没错过
Dean, the angel hasn't been wrong yet.
有人要做可怕的事 而我能制止他
Someone's gonna do something awful and I can stop it.
还有人说你也会变坏呢 萨姆
You're supposed to be bad too, Sam.
也许我应该现在就制止你
Maybe I should just stop you right now.
知道吗 迪恩？我就是不明白 你为什么都不肯考虑一下这种可能性？
Dean, I don't understand. Why can't you even consider the possibility?
- 什么可能性 你是说那东西是天使？- 对
- What, that this is an angel? - Yes!
我们也许在猎杀一个天使 我们应该停手
Maybe we're hunting an angel here and we should stop.
也许这是上帝的意志
Maybe this is God's will.
好了 好了 我明白你的意思了 你有信仰了
Okay. All right. You know what? I get it.
这 嘿 这很好 肯定能让你的日子好过点
You've got faith. Hey, good for you. I'm sure it makes things easier.
告诉你 还有一个像你一样有信仰的 就是妈妈
I'll tell you who else had faith like that: Mom.
她给我盖被子的时候告诉我 天使会保护我们
She used to tell me when she tucked me in that angels were watching over us.
实际上这是她对我说的最后一句话
In fact, that was the last thing she said to me.
- 你从没告诉过我 - 有什么可说的？
- You never told me that. - What's to tell?
她错了
She was wrong.
那时候没有人保护她
There was nothing protecting her.
这世上没有神灵 没有上帝
There's no higher power, there's no God.
只有混乱 暴力和无序
I mean, there's just chaos and violence.
还有不知从哪儿来的无法预知的魔鬼
Random, unpredictable evil that comes out of nowhere...
把你撕成碎片
and rips you to shreds.
你想要我相信天使？
So you want me to believe in this stuff?
那我需要确凿的证据 你有吗？
I'm gonna need to see some hard proof. You got any?
我可有
Well, I do.
能够证明我们对付的是个恶灵的证据
Proof that we're dealing with a spirit.
- 这好像是… - 苦艾
- It looks like... - It's wormwood.
在死人附近生长的草 特别是没有安息的死者
Plant associated with the dead. Specifically, the ones that are not at rest.
别处可没看到这种草 除了被谋杀的神父的墓碑上
I don't see it growing anywhere else, except over the murdered priest's marker.
就是他 萨姆
It's him, Sam.
也许
Maybe.
- 也许？- 迪恩 我不知道该怎么办了
- Maybe? - Dean, I don't know what to think.
好吧
Okay.
想要更多证据？那我就给你更多证据
You want some more proof? I'll give you more proof.
怎么？
How?
召唤格雷戈瑞的鬼魂
We'll summon Gregory's spirit.
什么？
What?
在这儿？教堂里？
Here? In the church?
对
Yeah.
没错 我们只要准备些工具 爸爸的笔记里有降灵术
Yeah, we just need a few odds and ends and that seance ritual in Dad's journal.
降灵术？好啊 要是有狂欢就更好了
Oh, seance, great. Hope Whoopi's available.
有趣 真有趣 说真的
That's funny, actually. Seriously.
如果格雷戈瑞神父的鬼魂在附近 就会被降灵术召唤出来
If Father Gregory's spirit is around, the seance will bring him right to us.
如果是他干的 我们就让他安息
If it's him, then we'll put him to rest.
但如果真是天使 它就不会出现
But if it's an angel, it won't show.
- 什么也不会发生 - 没错
- Nothing will happen. - Exactly.
这就是干咱们这行的好处之一 萨姆 不用为信仰争论
It's one of the perks of the job. We don't have to operate on faith.
我们有确认的办法
We can know for sure.
难道你不想知道吗？
Don't you wanna know for sure?
老兄… 好吧 我承认我们以前也用过
Dude, all right, I'll admit, we've gone pretty ghetto...
不少咒语 可这种还是第一次
with spell work before, but this takes the cake.
我是说 用海绵宝宝的垫子代替祭坛布？
I mean, a SpongeBob placemat instead of an altar cloth?
海绵宝宝那面往下不就行了
We'll just put it SpongeBob side down.
- 迪恩 就是那个 - 什么？
- Dean, that's it. - What?
那就是"信号"
That's the sign.
- 哪儿？- 就在那家伙身后
- Where? - Right there. Right behind that guy.
就是他 迪恩
That's him, Dean.
我们得阻止他
We have to stop him.
- 等会儿 - 你干吗？放开我
- Wait a minute. - What are you doing? Let me go.
我不会被一个鬼魂唆使去杀人吧？你疯了？
You're not gonna kill somebody because a ghost told you. Are you insane?
我不是要杀他 只是想阻止他
I'm not insane. I'm not gonna kill him, I'm gonna stop him.
怎么阻止 嗯？你要怎么做？
Define "stop, " huh? I mean, what are you gonna do?
迪恩 求你了 他会伤害某人 你知道的
Dean, please. He's gonna hurt someone, you know it.
好吧 来吧
All right. Come on.
迪恩
Dean.
打开车门
Unlock my door.
我不会让你杀人 萨姆 我跟着那家伙 你去降灵
You're not killing anyone, Sam. I got this guy, you go do the seance.
迪恩
Dean.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
这是什么？
What is this?
神父 我可以解释的
Father, please. I can explain. Uh...
不过也许我没法解释 呃…
Actually, maybe I can't. Um...
这是… 一种降灵术
This is, uh, a seance.
降灵术？年轻人 这里可是神之殿堂
A seance? Young man, you are in a house of God.
其实这个降灵术 是来源于早期基督教的仪式的
It's based on early Christian rites, if that helps any.
够了 你跟我来
Enough. You're coming with me.
神父 求你了 再等一会儿
Father, please, you-Just wait a second.
哦 天哪
Oh, my God.
那是…
Is that...?
天使吗？
Is that an angel?
不 不是
No, it's not.
只是格雷戈瑞神父的鬼魂
It's just Father Gregory.
托马斯
Thomas.
我是来回应你的祈祷的
I've come in answer to your prayers.
萨姆…
Sam.
我已经给你指出了路 你应该快点
I thought I sent you on your path. You should hurry.
神父 很抱歉
Father, I'm sorry.
但你不是天使
But you're not an angel.
我当然是
Of course I am.
不是
No.
你是个人 是鬼魂
You're a man. You're a spirit.
你应该安息
And you need to rest.
我曾经是人
I was a man.
但现在是天使
But now I'm an angel.
当时我在教堂的台阶上
I was on the steps of the church.
感到子弹穿透了我的身体
I felt that bullet pierce right through me.
但我并没感觉到痛苦
But there was no pain.
然后突然我能看到…
And then suddenly, I could see...
一切了
everything.
雷诺神父 我看到了你… 在这里祈祷 哭泣
Father Reynolds, I saw you praying and crying here.
我是来帮助你的
I came to help you.
怎么帮助我？
Help me how?
妈的
Damn it.
那些谋杀…
Those murders...
都是因为你？
that was because of you?
我听到了上帝的声音
I received the word of God.
他让我惩罚那些罪人
He spoke to me, told me to smite the wicked.
- 我在实现他的意愿 - 你让那些无辜的人去杀人
- I'm carrying out his will. - You're driving innocent people to kill.
那些无辜的人是在救赎
Those innocent people are being offered redemption.
有些人需要救赎
Some people need redemption.
对吧 萨姆？
Don't they, Sam?
这怎么能叫救赎？
How can you call this redemption?
你现在还无法理解
You can't understand it now.
但人类的规矩和上帝的规则是不同的
The rules of man and the rules of God are two very different things.
那些人…
Those people...
他们被关起来了
they're locked up.
不 他们很幸福
No, they're happy.
他们得到了平静 打败了内心的魔鬼
They've found peace, beaten their demons.
- 我给了他们通向天堂的钥匙 - 不
- And I've given them the keys to heaven. - No.
不 这是复仇 这是错的
No. This is vengeance, it's wrong.
托马斯 这违背了你所相信的一切
Thomas, this goes against everything you believed.
你被迷惑 被误导了
You're lost, misguided.
神父… 不 我没有被误导
Father, no, I'm not misguided.
你不是天使 托马斯
You are not an angel, Thomas.
人不会变成天使
Men cannot be angels.
但是…
But...
但是我 我不明白
But I don't understand.
- 你祈祷着我的到来 - 我祈祷上帝的帮助 而不是这个
- You prayed for me to come. - I prayed for God's help. Not this.
你所作的事情不是上帝的意愿
What you're doing is not God's will.
"勿杀人"
Thou shalt not kill.
这才是上帝的教导
That's the word of God.
为什么停车？
How come we stopped?
呃 我们不是要去看电影吗？
Um, weren't we gonna go to the movies?
我们应该快点 要迟到了
Uh, we should go or we're gonna be late Aah!
对不起 我只是 从来没有这么做过
Uh, I'm sorry, I'm sorry. It's just I've never done this before.
看 我已经说了对不起
Look, I said I was sorry.
求求你…
Please.
什么
What?
不
No.
别动
Don't!
停下来
Stop it. Aah!
- 你还好吗？没事吧？- 感谢上帝
- Are you okay? Are you okay? - Thank God.
见鬼 你真的没事？
Damn it. Are you sure you're okay?
有手机吗？拨911
Do you have a cell phone? Call 911.
让我们帮助你
Let us help you.
不
No.
你该安息了 托马斯 长眠吧
It's time to rest, Thomas, to be at peace.
请让我给你做临终圣礼吧
Please, let me give you last rites.
天上的圣灵啊 我以上帝的仆从的名义请求你们
O holy hosts above, I call upon thee as a servant of Christ...
以上帝之名祝福我们今天的仪式
to sanctify our actions this day in fulfillment of the will of God.
雷诺神父？
Father Reynolds?
安息吧
Rest.
我请求天使长拉斐尔
I call upon the Archangel Raphael...
天空的守护神 打开通道
master of the air, to make open the way.
让圣灵之火降临
Let the fire of the Holy Spirit now descend...
让这个灵魂在另一个世界苏醒
that this being might be awakened to the world beyond.
哦…
Holy...
你那边怎么样？
How was your day?
你是对的
You were right.
不是天使 是格雷戈瑞
It wasn't an angel. It was Gregory.
我不知道 迪恩 我只是…
I don't know, Dean. I just, um...
我想要相信…
I wanted to believe...
真的非常想要相信
so badly I'd...
但实在太困难了…
It's so damn hard to do this...
我们做的这些事…
what we do.
那么孤单
All alone, you know.
这世界上有那么多邪恶的东西 我都快窒息了
And there's so much evil out in the world, Dean, I feel like I could drown in it.
我一想起我的命运 一想起我以后会变成什么…
And when I think about my destiny, when I think about how I could end up...
别担心那个 好么？
Yeah, well, don't worry about that, all right?
有我罩着你呢
I'm watching out for you.
是啊 我知道你会的
Yeah, I know you are.
但你只是个人 迪恩
But you're just one person, Dean.
我还需要去思考一些其他的东西 你知道吗？
And I needed to think there was something else watching too, you know?
比如… 神灵
Some higher power.
比如某种善良的力量
Some greater good.
那样也许…
And that maybe...
也许什么？
Maybe what?
也许我能被拯救
Maybe I could be saved.
但是 你知道 这种想法蒙蔽了我的判断力
But, uh, you know, that just clouded my judgment.
你是对的
And you're right.
我是说 我们只该相信我们了解的
We gotta go with what we know, with what we can see...
相信我们亲眼看到的
with what's right there in front of our own two eyes.
有意思 你居然会这么说
Yeah, well, it's funny you say that.
为什么？
Why?
格雷戈瑞的鬼魂告诉你的没错
Gregory's spirit gave you some pretty good information.
那个家伙不是个好东西
The guy in the car was bad news.
我差点就来不及了
I barely got there in time.
出什么事了？
What happened?
他死了
He's dead.
- 难道你… - 不是
- Did you...? - No.
不过我告诉你
But I'll tell you one thing. If...
他死的方式如果不是亲眼所见
The way he died, if I hadn't seen it with my own two eyes...
我一辈子都不会相信
I never would've believed it.
我是说…
I mean...
我不知道该怎么说
I don't know what to call it.
什么？
What?
迪恩 你看到了什么？
Dean, what did you see?
也许…
Maybe...
是上帝的旨意
God's will.